# Miguel Ramos

## **Full Stack Developer**

Vancouver, WA

360-980-0308 | <u>drexelramos@gmail.com</u> LinkedIn | GitHub | Portfolio

## **OBJECTIVE**

Self-motivated and accomplished business professional with over 10 years of experience within sales and financial services industry. Helped develop ecommerce website for cannabis company which processes over \$1.2M in sales annually. Looking to leverage extensive background in sales, problem-solving and effective communication into a new career as a Full Stack Developer.

## **SKILLS**

#### **Front End**

HTML5 | CSS3 | Sass jQuery | JavaScript ES6 React | React Hooks | JSX Bootstrap | Materialize

#### **Back End**

Node.js | MongoDB PostgreSQL | Express

#### Additional Tools/Skills

Git | GitHub | npm Postman | Jest | Enzyme WordPress | Airtable RESTful APIs | Figma

## **Professional Skills**

Problem-Solving Critical Thinking Creativity | Collaboration Effective Communication

#### **PROJECTS**

## Heavenly Buds | Live Site Link

- Collaborated to create ordering website for cannabis company increasing sales 140%
- Conceptualized custom design to reflect company branding and image
- Developed wireframes for improved UI/UX and logical website navigation. Coding done by freelancer
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | WordPress

#### Stocks Analysis | Project Link | GitHub

- Thinkful API project Created application to retrieve company's financial & stock information from multiple APIs
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript | jQuery | RESTful APIs

## Natours | Project Link | GitHub

- Thinkful project Responsive website for company providing nature tours utilizing advanced Sass visual effects
- Tech: HTML | CSS | Sass | JavaScript

#### Omnifood | Project Link | GitHub

- Thinkful project Responsive SPA for food delivery company utilizing advanced HTML and CSS
- Tech: HTML | CSS | JavaScript

### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Developer

#### Freelance | Vancouver, WA (remote)

January 2021 - Present

- Web development for businesses & non-profits
- Develop UI/UX strategies including wireframes and mockups
- Design, code & create websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript and React

#### Account Manager

#### American Fidelity | Portland, OR (remote)

September 2019 - Present

- Achieved multiple insurance & investment licenses Life, Health, Series 63, Series 6
- Analyze financial and personal data to create customized health and retirement plans for employees in the Education Sector
- Utilize Salesforce as a CRM, online scheduling tool, ordering for marketing materials and customer service center

#### Territory Sales Manager

#### Kornerstone Credit | Seattle, WA (remote)

- August 2018 September 2019
- Exceptional performance selling alternative financing options to auto repair shops and furniture retailers utilizing consultative solutions-based sales approach
- Helped grow this startup company from \$0 to over \$6 million in monthly company funding
- Successfully grew regional merchant partner base from 0 to over 120 locations
- Executed user testing on lending application to simplify transaction processing and increase loan approval rates

#### Property Manager

#### CM3 Real Estate | Vancouver, WA (remote)

May 2017 - November 2018

- Negotiated, purchased and sold real estate in multiple states
- Developed ecommerce site for selling real estate which decreased days on market by 50%
- Created SPA for purchasing real estate and implemented processes for automating the screening procedure of sellers increasing efficiency and scalability and decreasing phone time by 8 hours per week
- Created videos and digital marketing campaigns across many social media platforms and industry channels

## Territory Sales Executive

#### Western Union | Seattle, WA (remote)

September 2005 - May 2017

- Received multiple awards for exceptional Teamwork and Sales results President's Club, Achiever Award, Driven Award, MVP Award
- Conducted user testing on money transfer desktop and mobile applications resulting in better UX, increased revenue and 15% higher app utilization within existing customers
- Trained 12 new employees on sales techniques, Compliance and Anti-Money Laundering policies and procedures
- Utilized Salesforce as a CRM and troubleshooting customer service tickets

#### **EDUCATION**

B.A. in Computer Science & Information Science

#### **Drexel University**

• Minored: Business & Mathematics

## Software Engineering

#### Thinkful

• Learned industry best practices and practical software development standards with a focus on full stack mobile-first applications, algorithms and data structures